http://www.ncbon.org/legalnotices/privacystatement

HomeLicensure & Listing
OverviewNurse GatewayVerify a LicenseApply
Renewal-Reinstatement (RN-LPN)Licensure by Examination (NCLEX®)Licensure by EndorsementNurse Aide II (NA II)Request Inactive or Retired StatusRequest Name or Address ChangeCriminal Background Check / Live Scan
Advanced Practice Registered Nurse (APRN)
Advanced Practice Registered Nurse (APRN) RequirementsCompact State ApplicationControlled Substances Reporting System (CSRS)Nurse PractitionerCertified Nurse MidwifeCertified Registered Nurse AnesthetistClinical Nurse Specialist
Continuing CompetenceRefresher CourseNurse Licensure CompactNursys e-Notify
Education
OverviewEducation SummitContinuing Education
OverviewBoard Sponsored Offerings
Continuing Education OfferingsUnderstanding the Scope of Practice and Role of the Licensed Practical NurseLegal Scope of Practice Online Course (Individual)Legal Scope of Practice Online Course (Nursing Program Directors)On-Site Workshops
Board Sponsored Bulletin Offerings
Nursing Regulatory Agencies and Advocacy Organizations: What is the Difference?Continuing Education OfferingsImplications for use of Marijuana and Marijuana Containing Products Among NursesAm I Within My Scope?Protect Your Nursing License: Safe Handling, Administration, and Documentation of Controlled SubstancesContinuing Competence Self-Assessment: Have You Met Your Professional Responsibility?Maintaining Professional Boundaries in NursingGetting to Know Your Licensing Board: the North Carolina Board of Nursing at a GlanceWhat Nurses need to know about Informatics, Social Media, and Security!Development of Sanctioning Guidelines for Public Discipline in Nursing Regulation: The North Carolina Board of Nursing JourneyWhat Could Happen: The Consequences of "Practice Drift"… Is it Worth the Risk?Creating a Healthy Work Environment is Every Nurses' ResponsibilitySocial Networking and NursesWho's Your Supervisor or Manager? Nursing Practice: The Management and Supervision of Nursing ServiceUh oh, the Board of Nursing called...Complaint Reporting and ResolutionDELEGATION: What are the Nurse's Responsibilities?Fitness for Duty includes Getting Your ZZZZsIncivility in NursingCompetency Validation: What Does it Mean for You?Public Protection Through Safe Nurse Staffing Practice
Request a Board of Nursing SpeakerCNE Approval
Programs in North Carolina
Information & RulesApproved Pre-Licensure Nursing Programs
General InformationBaccalaureate DegreeDiploma in Registered NursingAssociate DegreeDiploma in Practical Nursing
RN to BSNGraduate EducationMSNDoctorate
Internationally Educated NursePrograms Outside of North CarolinaResources for Program Directors
OverviewEducation Consultant AssignmentsJust Culture InformationApproval of Program ExpansionAssessing a Clinical AgencySuggestion for Utilization of PreceptorsEducation CommuniqueSimulation Guidance
Resources for StudentsStatistics/NCLEXMedication Aide Curriculum
Medication Aide Information, Laws & RulesCertification as Registered Nurse InstructorRe-Certification as Registered Nurse InstructorProgram Revision-UpdatesTeaching Medication Aide ClassClass Supply ChecklistAvailable Courses
Unlicensed Assistive Personnel
Medication Administration Teaching ModulesTeaching Modules for Nurse Aide II TasksApproved Nurse Aide II CoursesNurse Aide II Competency Assessment CoursesNurse Aide II Competency Assessment RequirementsNurse Aide II Course Guidelines
Position StatementsFrequently Asked Questions
Practice
OverviewRegistered NurseLicensed Practice NurseNurse AidesMedication AidesSexual Assault Nurse ExaminerAdvanced Practice Registered NurseNurse Practitioner
General InformationNurse Practitioner Laws & RulesPrescribingBack-up Supervising PhysicianCollaborative Practice GuidelinesCompliance Review MaterialsContinuing Education RequirementsInformation at Practice SiteRefresher CourseNurse Practitioner Application ProcessesPosition StatementFrequently Asked Questions
Certified Registered Nurse AnesthetistCertified Nurse MidwifeClinical Nurse SpecialistProfessional Corporations and Professional Limited Liability CompaniesPosition Statements & Decisions TreesFrequently Asked Questions
Discipline & Compliance
OverviewPublic ComplaintEmployer Complaint
Should I Report?Event Investigation GuideJust Culture Overview
General InformationConcepts and DefinitionsJust Culture Podcasts
Complaint Evaluation Tool (CET)Student Practice Event Evaluation Tool (SPEET)
Self-ReportInvestigation & Resolution
InvestigationResolutionFrequently Asked Questions
Reinstatement Following DisciplineDrug Monitoring ProgramsChemical Dependency ResourcesChild Support DelinquencyDisciplinary Actions Log
Laws & Rules
OverviewNursing Practice ActAdministrative Code-Rules
Board of Nursing
General InformationBoard of Nursing Proposed Rule Adoption and Amendments
Midwifery
General InformationMidwifery Joint Committee
Rule Making Notification
Badge Law, License Required and Exceptions
Board Information
OverviewHistorical InformationMission, Vision and ValuesAwardsGovernance
Board MembersDuties and ResponsibilitiesBoard and Committee MeetingsBoard MinutesStrategic Plan
Election
General InformationQualificationsNominationState Ethics ActVotingElection Results
Board Member Sign-in
News, Publications & Statistics
Important Information about COVID-19News & AnnouncementsCalendar of EventsConsumer InformationData Requests & ApplicationFrequently Asked Questions
Knowledge BaseComplaintsControlled Substance Reporting SystemCriminal Background Check-Live ScanDisaster Relief in North CarolinaInvestigation & ResolutionLicensure by EndorsementLicensure by ExaminationNurse Aide IINurse GatewayNurse Licensure CompactNursing EducationNursing PracticeNurse PractitionerRenewal-ReinstatementVerify a License
Online Services, Forms & ApplicationsPodcastsPublications
Current Nursing BulletinArchived Nursing BulletinsAnnual Report
Statistics
Statistics By Nursing DesignationStatistics for NCLEXNursing Education TrendsMiscellaneous Statistics Archive
Contact Us
Contact UsStaff DirectoryEmployment OpportunitiesHelpVisual Sitemap
Test
Visual StylingBootstrapVisual Styling 2ElectionTest 1GovernanceBoard of Nursing
I want to...
View Temporary Waivers
Lookup a License
Request External Verification
View Disciplinary Action Logs-Public Documents
Sign Up for Nursys e-Notify
Renew RN-LPN License
Reinstate RN-LPN License
Request RN-LPN Inactive-Retired Status
Apply for NCLEX-RN/PN
Apply for Re-Examination (NCLEX-RN/PN)
Transfer RN-LPN License (Endorsement/Reciprocity)
Complete Criminal Background Check-Live Scan
Renew NA II Listing
Submit NA II Initial Listing
Submit Compact State Application (APRN)
Submit Advanced Practice Approval-Recognition
Complete NA II Employment Verification
Complete Program Verification
Request Name-Address Change
Request Data-Mailing List
File Complaint/Self-Report
View Statistics
Access FAQ Knowledge Base
View Nursing Practice Act
Board Member Sign-in
Privacy Statement...
North Carolina Board of Nursing (NCBON) is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the NCBON Web site and governs data collection and usage. By using the NCBON website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.
Collection of your Personal Information
NCBON collects personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. NCBON also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by NCBON. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used by NCBON for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the NCBON Web site. Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through NCBON public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: NCBON does not read any of your private online communications. NCBON encourages you to review the privacy statements of Web sites you choose to link to from NCBON so that you can understand how those Web sites collect, use and share your information. NCBON is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on Web sites outside of the NCBON and NCBON family of Web sites.
Use of your Personal Information
NCBON collects and uses your personal information to operate the NCBON Web site and deliver the services you have requested. NCBON also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from NCBON and its affiliates. NCBON may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.
NCBON keeps track of the Web sites and pages our customers visit within NCBON, in order to determine what NCBON services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within NCBON to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.
Use of Cookies
The NCBON Web site use "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.
One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize NCBON pages, or register with NCBON site or services, a cookie helps NCBON to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same NCBON Web site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the NCBON features that you customized.
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the NCBON services or Web sites you visit.
Security of your Personal Information
NCBON secures your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. NCBON secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other Web sites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.
Social Media
The NCBON on Facebook is moderated. That means all comments will be reviewed before posting. In addition, the NCBON expects that participants will treat each other with respect. The NCBON on Facebook will not post comments that contain vulgar or abusive language; personal attacks of any kind; or offensive terms that target specific ethnic or racial groups. The NCBON on Facebook will not post comments that are spam, or are clearly “off topic." Comments that make unsupported accusations will also be subject to review.
Here is a summary of the guidelines we abide by:
The use of vulgar, offensive, threatening or harassing language is prohibited. Public comments should be limited to comments related to the topic.  The NCBON on Facebook is not the proper place to express opinions or beliefs not directly related to that topic.
Changes to this Statement
NCBON will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. NCBON encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how NCBON is protecting your information.
Contact Information
NCBON welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that NCBON has not adhered to this Statement, please contact NCBON. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
North Carolina Board of Nursing
Protect the public
by regulating the practice of nursing.
Sitemap
Copyright © 2020North Carolina Board of NursingAll rights reserved
